[Music]
Hello everyone and welcome back
to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and
today we're talking about
something that has always
been very confusing for me.
For me as well, I don't understand
very well what this is about.
We're going to be
talking about time zones
and a little bit about
daylight savings time.
Before we get started
though, let's take a look
at this phrase in today's
vocabulary preview.
Very vocabulary preview.
All right so the phrase
is daylight savings time.
Okay so we're trying to
save daylight pretty
much. That's right so this
is the time of year when
we change our clocks.
What does that mean?
That means in the fall
there's a special day and
everyone has it on their
calendar and we change the
clocks we put them back one hour.
So if it was eight o'clock
now it's seven o'clock.
Okay so everything
is earlier, starts
earlier and that's basically
to take advantage of
the daylight right? That's why
it's called daylight savings time.
Exactly and so
that's for the winter
and then when the winter is
passed we change the clocks again.
We have the spring
daylight savings
where we change our clocks
ahead. Okay so it sounds
kind of complicated.
Many countries don't have
daylight savings time.
They don't change their
clocks at all but we're
going to be talking about
this in a little bit more so why don't we
listen to our dialogue for the first time.
Did you set your clock forward
for daylight savings time?
What? Why do we have to do that?
Well at the start of the
spring we usually have
more daylight in the mornings
and less than the afternoon.
This is basically due to our position on
the planet and the rotation of the earth.
In any case to take better
advantage of the daylight
available we compensate
by moving our clocks
forward one out. I
see that's convenient.
I never understood things
like this such as GMT.
I never know what time zone we
are in or when to change my clock.
That just stands for
Greenwich meantime.
Here in California we're
in Pacific Standard Time.
That is eight time
zones west of Greenwich.
Remember when
we were in Beijing?
Well then we were in China
Standard Time and that's eight
time zones east of
Greenwich. That's why it was
so weird traveling from
Beijing to LA because of
a huge time difference.
Even though we left
Beijing at noon in flu
for more than eight hours
we still arrived in LA the same day
at noon. It's like we went back in time.
All right we're back so that was a pretty
clear explanation of why we do these things
but maybe there are a
couple of words that you
didn't understand so let's
take a look at those now
in language takeaway.
Well Marco what you were
hinting at before this idea
that we have shorter days
in the winter and longer
days in the summer has
to do with the rotation
of the earth and so the
rotation of the earth
is our first phrase.
Okay so the earth rotates
what does that mean if it rotates?
It means to spin around
but not just to spin
around anywhere. It
means that if you draw a line
through the middle of
something it never leaves that
line it just kind of turns.
Okay so it's spinning
like the wheels on a car
they rotate that means
they go around but
they are fixed to the car
to the car right so this
is one of the reasons why
we need to compensate
our clocks because of the
rotation of the earth and
that's our next word to
compensate this is a verb
to compensate and it's
often used with money but it
can be used with time as well.
Time or sunlight so
with money you'd say
I paid him a hundred
dollars but I owed him a
hundred fifty so I'm going to
compensate him for the extra fifty.
Okay means I'm going to fix it.
Okay so two compensate would
be the verb and compensation
would be the noun.
Now in this case we're
talking about time so how
can we compensate time?
Well that means that
if we have lost an hour
because we change the
clocks we have to compensate
we have to try and gain
an hour back and so that's
why in the spring after
the days start to get
longer and longer we're
to compensate for that by
changing the clocks again.
Okay so we're compensating
time. Now related to
daylight savings and this
whole time thing is time
zones. We have time zones
all over the earth and
you've probably noticed this
if you've traveled you
have to change your clocks
or many times you see
in hotels what time it
is in London and Hong
Kong and Berlin etc.
And this makes a lot
of sense because like we
said the earth is rotating
and so if it's daylight
in Moscow and it's nighttime
in New York obviously
it's not the same time.
Right. So to compensate
for this difference
we have different time
zones and each time
zone is pretty much an hour
so you know half an hour
different from the next one.
Right so most countries
actually have different
time zones throughout
their country unless they're
small that they don't
really need to compensate
any change or for
example China just to unify
everything it's a big
country but they have one
time zones China standard
time. Exactly but in the
United States we
have four times a right.
All right so that's time zone
and out related to time zone is
time difference. Okay
well think about math here
difference is a word
that we use in math and a
time difference is the
amount of time that means
how many hours there
are between one time zone
and another time zone.
So for example Beijing
and New York City these
are very very far away
from each other it's
day in in New York it's
night in Beijing so
that means if it's seven
in the morning in Beijing
it's probably around
seven at night in New
York. So the time difference
would be more or less
12 hours. Exactly but when
it's daylight savings
time it's 13 so be careful.
Right okay I think
that's pretty clear I think
we should go back and
listen to our dialogue
again and we'll be back
soon with Fluency Builder.
Did you set your cook forward
for daylight savings time?
What? Why do we have to do that?
Well at the start of the
spring we usually have
more daylight in the mornings
and less in the afternoon.
This is basically due to our position on
the planet and the rotation of the earth.
In any case to take
better advantage of the
daylight available we
compensate by moving our
clocks forward one hour.
I see that's convenient.
I never understood things
like this such as GMT.
I never know what time
zone we are in or when to
change my clock. That just
stands for Greenwich meantime.
Here in California we're
in Pacific Standard Time.
That is eight time
zones west of Greenwich.
Remember when we were in Beijing? Well then
we were in China Standard Time and that's
eight time zones
east of Greenwich.
That's why it was so weird
traveling from Beijing to LA
because of the
huge time difference.
Even though we left Beijing
at noon in flu for more than
eight hours we still arrived
in LA the same day at noon.
It's like we went back in time.
Alright we're back so now let's take a look
at three key phrases in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder. Oh let's
go back to the beginning
of this dialogue. The
person who's explaining
all of these interesting
things is saying that
well in any case to take
better advantage of the
daylight available we
compensate by moving our
clocks forward one hour.
So this is an important
phrase you could say to
take better advantage of
or to take advantage of. Let's talk
about this to take advantage of something.
So to take advantage of something
is to use it efficiently, right?
Or to take better
advantage. So for example
if you drive to work every
day and your neighbor
drives to work every day
and you work at the same
place you could take
better advantage of your car
and the cost by sharing
the same car to work.
Exactly or when people
started to use computers you
could say well they were
taking better advantage
of their time by speeding
things up by making
things faster with the
computers. Right or many
mothers say take better
advantage of your time
and read something instead
of playing those video games.
Exactly so it
means like you said
to be more efficient to do
useful or important things.
That's right and now
when we talked about
what daylight savings
time means or GMT what
that stands for. This is an
interesting phrase it stands for.
Well think about
it as a picture so
if something stands for
something else that means
the original thing
it's not there anymore.
And so in words and phrases
like GMT you GMT doesn't mean
anything by itself but the
G stands for something.
The M stands it's an
acronym. Okay so this is an
acronym that stands for that
represents three big long words.
Okay Greenwich mean time.
Right so we use this a lot
when we are defining words or
when we are defining an
acronym like GMT stands
for Greenwich mean time
or for example USA stands
for United States of
America. Or we can even say
someone's name
stands for something.
So Marco what is the M in
your last name stand for so your
Marco M what is the M
stand for. Right and then I
would say well it stands
for me here. Your last name.
Right so you can use
this when you see things
that you don't understand
maybe an acronym or an
abbreviation like does
Kathy stand for Catherine?
Yes Kathy stands for
Catherine it's a short
version of Catherine.
Cool all right and well
now talking a little bit
more about time you've
maybe seen the movie
back to the future and
this is what it's all
about to go back in time.
To go back in time so
we went back in time this
is what the person says about
the flight from Beijing to LA.
What's interesting is that to go back in
time is kind of a fixed phrase we always
say like this so we could
say if you went back
in time where would you
go what time what place?
Right so to go back in
time usually use it like
this now what if I wanted
to say to go into the
future could you say
go forward in time?
You could go forward in time
or you could go into the future?
Right go into the future
so remember if you
want to talk about going
back in time is usually
traveling to the past.
Exactly all right so that's
all the phrases we have
why don't we listen to
the dialogue for
the very last time.
Did you set your clock forward
for daylight savings time?
What? Why do we have to do that?
Well at the start of the spring
we usually have more daylight
in the mornings and
less than the afternoon.
This is basically due to
our position on the planet
and the rotation of
the earth. In any case to
take better advantage
of the daylight available
we compensate by moving
our clocks forward one hour.
I see that's convenient
I never understood
things like this such as
GMT. I never know what
time zone we are in or
when to change my clock.
That just stands for
Greenwich Mean Time.
Here in California we're
in Pacific Standard Time
that is eight time
zones west of Greenwich.
Remember when we were in
Beijing? Well then we were in
China Standard Time
and that's eight time zones
east of Greenwich.
That's why it was so weird
traveling from Beijing
to LA because of a huge
time difference. Even
though we left Beijing
at noon in flu for more
than eight hours we still
arrived in LA the same
day at noon. It's like
we went back in time.
All right we're back and
now this is actually
something that really does
happen right if you take
off in an airplane from
Beijing you fly for a
certain amount of hours
and you reach California
and it's still the same
time you reach it in the
same day. It's very strange
the same thing happens
to me when I go home so I
leave Shanghai and I
arrive in Chicago and I arrive
at the exact same time
I left on the same day.
So it's like a time never
passed. Now it's the longest
day of your entire life
because it's not 24 hours.
The flight is 14
hours. It's really 24
38 hours long right so it's
really intense and exhausting.
And then what happens is when you do the
opposite you go from Chicago to Shanghai
then you go into the
future pretty much right
because you left on a
Sunday but you arrive on a
Tuesday or in my case
yeah you leave on a Sunday
and you arrive on a
Monday and you lose half a
day of your life right
you're just sitting there
all some it goes past
you right yeah so it all
evens out in the end
right right so when you go
back or when you come
it all evens out you you
recover you you get
those hours of your life back
pretty much they're
not gone forever all right
so if you guys have any
questions any doubts
you can send us an email at
englishpot@plexuslanguage.
com or come to our
website englishpot.com
we hope to see you there ask away
and until next time everyone bye